David Weir

10 The Drive, Orlynn Park

Lusk Co. Dublin Ireland

Phone: 085 8229594

E-mail: daveweir98@gmail.com
Website: daveweir98.github.io
github.com/daveweir98

linkedin.com/in/david-weir-9072bb10a

Summary

Organized, punctual, can communicate well in a team, with a good work ethic from past experience, and a quick/avid learner. Keen interest in technology, sport and film. I have an interest specifically in both data science and android development.

Education

2015 - Present: BSc Computer Applications, Dublin City University

- First class honoursin first year.
- My course so far, has taught me skills such as the use of strategies in problem solving, working on my own initiative and many design and technical skills.
- Languages I have experience with from this course include Java, R, Python, SQL, x86 MASM Assembly, HTML & CSS.

2015: Leaving Certificate, Skerries Community College.

Work Experience

2016 - Present: Dixons Carphone. Part-time Sales Consultant.

• Allowed me to get a considerable amount of experience working with people, to help them make smart buying decisions.

2011 – 2016: G.D.L. Harford Farm. Part-time general purpose worker.

• Provided me with a good work ethic, it gave me more punctual habits, and ability to work rapidly with others to reach a deadline.

Skills and Achievements

Programming: I currently have an intermediate knowledge of Python, HTML & CSS, SQL, MASM x86 Assembly(Which I am continually trying to improve). I am also currently learning Java, and R as part of my course this year. You can view some of my code at github.com/daveweir98. I have also got a basic introduction to Javascript and Jquery.

Operating Systems: I have good knowledge of windows operating systems, and some experience troubleshooting in Windows. I also have a good understanding of Linux operating systems, I currently dual boot Windows and Ubuntu on my personal laptop.

Teamwork: I have taken part in numerous exercises as part of my GAA team which have allowed me to fit in well with a team of people. I have gained fair communication skills as part of my college experience.

Leadership: I held leadership roles as a part of a web design team and also as part of a problem solving group project in my college course. I was also captain of my under 16 GAA football team.

At the end of the college year, I was **campaign manager** for the successful election of the current DCU School of Computing and Engineering faculty rep. My duties included talking to students about the election, selling my candidate to them, and expressing the different plans that he had for the upcoming year.

References

Available upon request